<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruby on Sajal Kayan</title>
    <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/ruby.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruby on Sajal Kayan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/ruby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Messing with ROR</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/messing-with-ror.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 13:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/messing-with-ror.html</guid>
      <description>Last few weeks I have beed gazing over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubyonrails.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; web frameworks. Spent some time with both, read numerous &lt;strong&gt;ROR vs Django&lt;/strong&gt; posts. Even attended Django 1.0 launch party in Bangkok, to give the Django fanboys a chance to convince me into Django... I did look into both frameworks and have decided upon ROR for the following reasons.
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love the Ruby language syntax. Looks neater and less confusing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I have done some perl hacking last few months, shift to Ruby was easy.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Loads of gems available to do cool stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;When I first looked at Ruby, I started picking it up without much problems, however Python confuses my head.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t know a lot of SQL... need framework to do everything for me.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Got free tech support which is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/luke_bkk&#34;&gt;@luke_bkk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See point 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The thing is even if i outsource the development, the code needs to be in something which I am personally comfortable with. I am not a software development company, but in my line of work (online publishing), we regularly need to mess with stuff, tweak things, add features, thus the control needs to be there with us. Thats what differentiates us from the bulk. If you don&#39;t test and innovate few things, your website would suck like the online version of an English Newspaper in Thailand.

So about an hour into development, here is screenshot of my accomplishment so far. It displays a list of stories in a blog format.

&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.sajalkayan.com/ror.png&#34; alt=&#34;ROR screenshot&#34; width=&#34;464&#34; height=&#34;515&#34; /&gt;

If my project starts looking good I might consider GPLizing it... but thats a rare possibility... the main reason im making it is to have fun and get a command over whatever my site runs on.

Edit 1 : Added point 6 ...
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby class to fetch suggested keywords</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/ruby-class-fetch-suggested-keywords.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 22:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/ruby-class-fetch-suggested-keywords.html</guid>
      <description>I have recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/sajal/statuses/872225824&#34;&gt;ditched Perl and fell for Ruby&lt;/a&gt;. 

Here is a Ruby class which gets suggested keywords from yahoo API and presents it in a comma separated list. This might be useful for people who use Ruby to upload/edit multiple posts and need to tag them automagically.

This might be awfully simple for the hardcore guys, but for a noob like me, had I come across this example earlier it would have saved me an hour or so. Here it goes...

The Class :-
&lt;pre lang=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;# A ruby class to fetch suggested keywords using Yahoo&#39;s term Extraction API
 require &#39;rubygems&#39;
require &#39;xmlsimple&#39;
require &#39;net/http&#39;

class Tagger
  def content
    @content
  end
  def content=(content)
    @content = content
  end
    def appid
    @appid
  end
  def appid=(appid)
    @appid = appid
  end
  def initialize

  end
  def fetch
          url = URI.parse(&#39;http://search.yahooapis.com/ContentAnalysisService/V1/termExtraction&#39;)
      post_args = {
            &#39;appid&#39; =&amp;gt; appid,
            &#39;context&#39; =&amp;gt; content,
            &#39;output&#39; =&amp;gt; &#34;xml&#34;
      }
      resp1, xml_data = Net::HTTP.post_form(url, post_args)
      keywords = &#34;&#34;
      data = XmlSimple.xml_in(xml_data)
      data[&#39;Result&#39;].each do |item|
      keywords = keywords + item + &#34;, &#34;
      end
      return keywords
  end
end&lt;/pre&gt;
Download the class &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sajalkayan.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/08/tagger.rb&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Sample usage :
&lt;pre lang=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;require &#39;tagger&#39;
tagg = Tagger.new
tagg.appid =     &#39;GO_GET_YOUR_OWN!&#39;
tagg.content = &#34;The content of the post.....&#34;
puts tagg.fetch&lt;/pre&gt;

The appid is available from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.yahoo.com/wsregapp/&#34;&gt;Yahoo Developer Network&lt;/a&gt;
Limitations : Maximum 5000 queries per day per IP.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>