<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Sajal Kayan</title>
    <link>https://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/security.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Sajal Kayan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/security.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter logged me as someone else! Privacy FAIL!</title>
      <link>https://www.sajalkayan.com/twitter-logged-me-as-someone-else-privacy-fail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 17:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sajalkayan.com/twitter-logged-me-as-someone-else-privacy-fail.html</guid>
      <description>A while ago, clicking on the &#34;tweet&#34; button of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://failblog.org/2010/10/26/epic-fail-photos-xbox-message-win/&#34;&gt;funny FAIL&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/reader/&#34;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; gave me the scare of my life. 

First reaction: How did my twitter theme change?
Second reaction: When did i start tweeting/reading in Thai?
Third reaction: When did I change into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/994651514/32086_403053037679_556887679_4991310_709940_n_bigger.jpg&#34;&gt;pretty girl&lt;/a&gt;?

I was logged in as someone else! Thats probably what brain transplant(when possible) would feel like...

In other words, the transparent proxy at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thailandinternet.com/&#34; title=&#34;really crappy internet provider in Thailand&#34;&gt;True&lt;/a&gt; simply fucked up... can&#39;t do anything about it. There is probably someone else in Thailand having the time of his/her life browsing into my account and poking into my disgusting life...

So, the solution for me would be to use a secure tunnel bypassing True&#39;s evil session hijacking transparent proxy all together.. Which is kinda illegal I&#39;ve been told... and also who will protect me from all the porn(and evil propaganda) on the interwebs ;)

@kiqq_3112 : Ive tried to censor sensitive stuff from the screenshots, if you are offended by anything, give me a shout out ill remove it. Just wanted to show how serious is this issue.

Click on the images to see full size full page... (Private tweets were censored)

1) Woah I&#39;m not me I&#39;m her?!?!?!

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/woah-im-girl.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/woah-im-girl-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter security FAIL&#34; height=&#34;306&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

2) I can tweet as her!! (Note: I didn&#39;t actually click the tweet button)

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/i-can-tweet.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/i-can-tweet-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter security FAIL&#34; height=&#34;142&#34; width=&#34;505&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

3) Spy on DMs!

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/personal-DM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/personal-DM-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter security FAIL&#34; height=&#34;249&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

4) Replies Page..

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/replies.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/replies-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter security FAIL&#34; height=&#34;251&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

5) Change settings..

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/settings.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/settings-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter security FAIL&#34; height=&#34;388&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

6) Change password!!!!

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/Password.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/Password-small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter security FAIL&#34; height=&#34;419&#34; width=&#34;381&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.ticdn.com/sajal/twitter-sec/twitter-sec.zip&#34;&gt;Download all images&lt;/a&gt;
Disclaimer: I haven&#39;t broken into anyone else&#39;s account, I don&#39;t do such things. My photoshop skills are not good enough to be able to fake these. Moreover I don&#39;t even own a copy of photoshop.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Proxy using Squid</title>
      <link>https://www.sajalkayan.com/secure-proxy-using-squid.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 05:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sajalkayan.com/secure-proxy-using-squid.html</guid>
      <description>Had originally posted this on Friday, September 29th, 2006 during the peak of Takhsin&#39;s rampant blocking of websites and the blocking proxies were messing up often blocking un-blocked pages also.

It is very important to use a secure proxy if you browse the web from unsecure Networks.
The basic requirements are a Linux box in a location which is secure and another PC Linux or windows which may be in the unsecure location.

NOTE : Please excuse my newbieness. I do not provide any kind of waranty on this article, only hope that it may be useful or interesting to you.

For this article, the squid was setup on a CentOS based server and accessed from FC5 based notebook using Mozilla Firefox. The settings would be simillar for other distributions/ browsers.

This method is not to be used illegally to view government blocked websites. Please follow laws of the country you reside in.&lt;!--more--&gt;

On CentOS it is very easy to install squid using yum (note you must be root to continue with the instalation)
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;yum install squid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
On Debian based system :-
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;apt-get install squid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
For others/slackware :-

Download squid source file as a gzipped tar ball (squid-x.y-STABLE.tar.gz) available at http://www.squid-cache.org/ or from ftp://www.squid-cache.org/pub. Then run the following commands
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;tar -xvzf squid-*-src.tar.gz&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;cd squid -*&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;./configure&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;make install&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
This by default, will install in “/usr/local/squid”.

There are some basic configurations which you may need to edit.
By default the squid config file is located in /etc/squid/squid.conf on centos with squid installed using yum. Config file may be located at /usr/local/squid/etc/squid.conf if you have installed manually.

Start Squid on CentOS
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;/etc/init.d/squid start&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Squid is now ready to serve as proxy only to local host and is listening on port 3128

Now you have squid listening to localhost only. We need to make a tunnel from the server to the PC.
Note for windows users reffer to &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20070505081807/http://www.jfitz.com/tips/putty_config.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Secure tunnel on windows using putty &#34;&gt;putty configuration guide&lt;/a&gt;
to do this on a FC5 (Fedora core instructions may be similar for other distributions) be root(or superuser) and run the following command.
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;ssh -L 8080:localhost:3128 someserver.com -l username&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Replace the someserver.com with the DNS name or IP of your newly setup proxy server.
In case the SSHD on your server listens to aa port other than port 22, you may need to enter the following command
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;ssh -L 8080:localhost:3128 someserver.com -p 1022 -l username&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
In the above example:-
8080 is a free unused port on your PC. We will tunnel this port to squid.
localhost is your PC
3128 is the port on the proxy server where squid is listening to.
someserver.com is your proxy servers hostname or IP address.
1022 is the port on your server where SSHD listens to.
username is your username on the server

After entering the ssh command, you will get a prompt asking for a password. Enter the password for ‘username’.

Open Mozilla Firefox
Click Edit the preferences. Then click on the box Connection Settings
Choose Manual proxy configuration.
Under HTTP proxy type in localhost. For port type in 8080 (change it as per your tunnel settingings)
Then click OK

You should now be able to use the Web browser to surf the net using browsing the web without fear of packets being sniffed.
This only encrypts the information exchanged between your workstation and the proxy server. The information from your proxy to the website you are browsing can still be sniffed, so to be on the safe side use https when browsing sites which support it.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>