<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bccm on Sajal Kayan</title>
    <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/bccm.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bccm on Sajal Kayan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/bccm.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCampChiangMai - Only one week to go!</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/barcampchiangmai-only-one-week-to-go.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 09:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/barcampchiangmai-only-one-week-to-go.html</guid>
      <description>This coming Saturday the geeks of Thailand are gonna congregate at Chiang Mai for the very first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barcampchiangmai.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BarCamp at Chiang Mai&lt;/a&gt;. In fact May 2008 is the month for camping (ignore the heat and rain, geeks camp in Air Conditioned rooms). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/barcampchiangmai&#34;&gt;BarCampChiangMai&lt;/a&gt; on 17th May, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barcampbangkok.org/drupalcamp-overview&#34;&gt;DrupalCamp&lt;/a&gt; Bangkok on 24th May both of which I intend to attend and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barcampchiangmai.org/users/view/22&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;probably speak&lt;/a&gt; at if I manage to hack up something worth presenting about.
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.barcampchiangmai.org/img/logo_web.gif&#34; alt=&#34;BarCampChiangMai logo&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; vspace=&#34;10&#34; width=&#34;396&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sajalkayan.com/barcampbangkok-winter-2008-a-huge-success.html&#34; title=&#34;BarCampBangkok winter 2008 a HUGE success!&#34;&gt;HUGE success at BarCampBangkok&lt;/a&gt; has shown the Thai geeks the need for more such events. In fact some of the attendees of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/barcampbangkok&#34;&gt;BarCampBangkok&lt;/a&gt; have been organizing a monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/barcampbangkok4ever&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BarcampBangkok4Ever&lt;/a&gt; which is a smaller casual gathering of geeks at a coffee shop.

FYI
&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;em&gt;BarCamp is an international network of user-generated conferences — open, participatory workshop-events, whose content is provided by participants — often focusing on early-stage web applications, and related open source technologies, social protocols, and open data formats. The event will be bilingual, in both English and Thai.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is no audience, only participants. All participants should give a demo, a session, photos, videos or anything else. All presentation are scheduled immediately before the event by reserving slots at the venue.&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Anyone with something to contribute is welcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
The BarCamp at Chiang Mai would be organized on May 17, 2008 from 1000-1800 hrs at Payap University and is sponsored by Payap University, Codegent and Creative Hacker. With one more week to go &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barcampchiangmai.org/users/registrants/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;59 people have registered&lt;/a&gt; to participate. I would be staying the night of 17th at Chiang Mai and am &lt;strong&gt;looking for a roomie&lt;/strong&gt; for the night to share the room expense. In case anyone is interested please leave a comment.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>