<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Benq on Sajal Kayan </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://sajal.github.io/tag/benq.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 04:04:26 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open letter to Thailand&#39;s Software Bullies</title>
      <link>http://sajal.github.io/open-letter-to-thailands-software-bullies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 04:04:26 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sajal.github.io/open-letter-to-thailands-software-bullies.html</guid>
      <description>Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry I cant read your Thai only website)
Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Lenovo&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry cant find name of contact on your site)
Kind attn : Prasert Charoonpaisal - General Manager - Personal Systems Group (PSG) - &lt;strong&gt;HP&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand
Kind attn : Corporate Communications Dept. - &lt;strong&gt;Sony&lt;/strong&gt; Thai Co., Ltd.
Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Asus&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry I cant read your Thai only website)
Kind attn : Acer Head Office - &lt;strong&gt;Acer&lt;/strong&gt; Computer Co., Ltd.
Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Benq&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry I cant read your Thai only website)

Dear Sirs or Madams,

This is to bring to your notice that almost all notebooks available in Thailand come bundled with windows preloaded.

I had purchased a Sony VAIO 3 or 4 years ago which came bundled with Windows XP. Due to quality problems in the software provided, I had to switch over to a different Operating System. I have no claims on the licensing fee of the inferior software provided to me as during the time of purchase I had intended to use it, and I did for quite a while.

Now, the time has come for me to purchase a new notebook. A self conducted study at fortune town on June 20th 2008 reviled that almost &lt;strong&gt;all notebooks came with Windows pre-installed and the license bundled&lt;/strong&gt;. On asking any of the vendors that I don&#39;t want to pay for the license, I was informed it is impossible. The very limited selection of notebooks which do come without Windows pre-installed are bottom of the line models which are usually outdated or very heavy.

&lt;strong&gt;My questions to all of the addresses&lt;/strong&gt; :-
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do you assume a non-windows user to not be able to afford your mid-segment notebooks?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is your intention to force Linux users into buying a Windows license?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is this an effort to form a cartel against Linux?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Question to all the notebook vendors&lt;/strong&gt; :-
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do you refund any difference amount in case the buyer does not use the license?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Question to Lenovo&lt;/strong&gt; :-
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lenovo USA does offer an interesting range of notebooks without Windows. Does Lenovo Thailand do the same?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Question to Microsoft :-&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do you refund any unused windows License?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I am aware of the software piracy issues in Thailand, but have you ever conducted a study as to how many non-windows users own a windows license? Do you reduce this number when publishing piracy rates?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Please respond, via comment form below in English only. The replies would help me decide weather or not to get a new notebook here in Thailand or order it in the States or Singapore, potentially making the Thai Government suffer a loss of tax revenue.

PS : Apologies to other companies who fit my criteria and I missed them out! They are also free to respond.

Regards,
Sajal Kayan

Update 1 : Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bact&#34;&gt;@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bact.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;bact&lt;/a&gt; for translating to Thai and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blognone.com/node/8123&#34;&gt;publishing on blognone&lt;/a&gt;.

Update 2 : Online discussions at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blognone.com/node/8117&#34;&gt;blognone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.ubuntuclub.com/hardware/linux-notebooks/&#34;&gt;ubuntuclub&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>