<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Microsoft on Sajal Kayan </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/tag/microsoft.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 08:37:26 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typical interaction of Windows Vista</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/typical-interaction-of-windows-vista.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 08:37:26 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/typical-interaction-of-windows-vista.html</guid>
      <description>Vista : Are you sure?
User : Yes
Vista : Are you sure about being sure?
User : Yes
Vista : Are you sure about being sure about being sure?
User : Yes
Vista : Are you sure about being sure about being sure about being sure?
User : Yes
Vista : Are you sure about being sure about being sure about being sure about being sure?
User : Yes
Vista : Are you sure about being sure about being sure about being sure about being sure about being sure?
User : Yes
Vista : Are you sure about being sure about being sure about being sure about being sure about being sure about being sure?
User : Grrr.... Screw you Microsoft!!!!
Vista : Are you sure you want to screw Microsoft?
...
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good, The Bad and The Greedy!</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/the-good-the-bad-and-the-greedy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 05:39:58 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/the-good-the-bad-and-the-greedy.html</guid>
      <description>Usually wanting money is a good thing. It makes us work harder. Greed is actually a good thing. It is the only line of defense between working hard and being a full time couch potato. Occasionally greed makes us do things... really evil things..

&lt;strong&gt;The Good Greed :&lt;/strong&gt; FOSS (Free and Open Source Software) is the perfect example of the good greed. The developers are usually not concerned about the community, they have their own personal greedy reason for contributing to a project. The reasons may be many including(but not limited to) :
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;They develop it just cause they wanna use it.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Money - Contribute code because someone is paying you to do so or that you would be able to sell services based on it&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bragging rights - to raise social status, a pay raise, etc...&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Joy&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
As you see all the above reasons are selfish greedy reasons and its not a bad thing.

&lt;strong&gt;The Bad Greed :&lt;/strong&gt; Listing some of them who are at the top of my mind.

Most&lt;strong&gt; Propriety Software Vendors&lt;/strong&gt; (out of scope of this post to name them all, use your your imagination) - For these people the primary greed is to sell their software to the most number of &#34;&lt;strong&gt;consumers&lt;/strong&gt;&#34; and the highest possible price. This is where &#34;&lt;strong&gt;best performing&lt;/strong&gt;&#34; gets substituted for &#34;&lt;strong&gt;best selling&lt;/strong&gt;&#34;. The software provided is usually capable of performing better or having more features, but these are locked and made available to &#34;consumers&#34; who pay more.

Moreover, the source code for these softwares is mostly not available to the &#34;consumers&#34; so they get away with &#34;selling&#34; any crap they want. Most of the money spent by the &#34;consumers&#34; is spent on legal issues, marketing, propoganda, adverts, yatches and corporate retreats. A lot of the effort put by developers is actually spent on restricting &#34;consumers&#34; from performing tasks on their software rather than adding more functionality.

&lt;strong&gt;Telcom Operators&lt;/strong&gt; : These people are supposed to sell bandwidth, thats it. I realized thats so untrue after a recent event where the speaker was from a leading smartphone software manufacturer that the telcom networks make most of their money from VAS (Value Added Services). The downside is it adds value but not for the &#34;consumers&#34; but rather than the bank balance of the company. They charge ridiculous prices for simple things like ringtone downloads, etc where the cost of the bandwidth would be negligible compared to the total fees charged. Well thats not too bad, but the really bad part is they would do everything in their power to prevent their &#34;consumers&#34; from getting these content from elsewhere because then they would charge only for the bandwidth.

&lt;strong&gt;Device Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt; : I am talking about especially about Smartphones here. These people manufacture these wonderful devices, but not to simply sell it at a profit. They want to be able to bundle as much VAS(see previous paragraph) on it as possible. The most common form of their evilness is joining up with a telcom operator exclusively to offer the device along with a plan.

Take the example of Google&#39;s Android based phone. The device is available in the United States at the price of $177.99 (roughly 6,302.39 Baht) with a plan from T-Mobile and for $399 (roughly 13,971.07 Baht). These phones are available only to T-Mobile customers and are locked to this network. The rest of the world is too foreign to make use of this. A recent trip to Pantip Plaza(Bangkok&#39;s IT shopping Mall) showed a retailer selling the G1 for 19,900 Baht (Roughly $568.32) without any warranty. This device was unlocked(probably illegally) and most probably it is illegal to use the device with any other SIM card other than T-Mobile&#39;s. A portion of the price you pay for the device is probably going towards the lawyers who helped placed this ristriction in the first place.

There are many more examples, but the above ones are about the ones I feel strongest about.

&lt;strong&gt;So the in the bad greed, the &#34;consumers&#34; actually pay a lot of money to have their freedom taken away from them and become slaves.&lt;/strong&gt;

Coming from a Business family background, we were always tought that &#34;Buyer is God&#34; ... Apparently nowdays it isint true...


The bottomline is that Greed may or maynot be a bad thing, it is how you make it work for you. So from now on, be proud of your greediness and use it in your advantage to do better things. The next time someone blames you for being too greedy, your reaction to it would be totally based on how you utilize the greed.

For me, my biggest greed would be freedom. I am greedy for it and will not let anyone tell me otherwise.

Yours Greedily,
Sajal
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open letter to Thailand&#39;s Software Bullies</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/open-letter-to-thailands-software-bullies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 04:04:26 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/open-letter-to-thailands-software-bullies.html</guid>
      <description>Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry I cant read your Thai only website)
Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Lenovo&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry cant find name of contact on your site)
Kind attn : Prasert Charoonpaisal - General Manager - Personal Systems Group (PSG) - &lt;strong&gt;HP&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand
Kind attn : Corporate Communications Dept. - &lt;strong&gt;Sony&lt;/strong&gt; Thai Co., Ltd.
Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Asus&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry I cant read your Thai only website)
Kind attn : Acer Head Office - &lt;strong&gt;Acer&lt;/strong&gt; Computer Co., Ltd.
Kind attn : &lt;strong&gt;Benq&lt;/strong&gt; Thailand (Sorry I cant read your Thai only website)

Dear Sirs or Madams,

This is to bring to your notice that almost all notebooks available in Thailand come bundled with windows preloaded.

I had purchased a Sony VAIO 3 or 4 years ago which came bundled with Windows XP. Due to quality problems in the software provided, I had to switch over to a different Operating System. I have no claims on the licensing fee of the inferior software provided to me as during the time of purchase I had intended to use it, and I did for quite a while.

Now, the time has come for me to purchase a new notebook. A self conducted study at fortune town on June 20th 2008 reviled that almost &lt;strong&gt;all notebooks came with Windows pre-installed and the license bundled&lt;/strong&gt;. On asking any of the vendors that I don&#39;t want to pay for the license, I was informed it is impossible. The very limited selection of notebooks which do come without Windows pre-installed are bottom of the line models which are usually outdated or very heavy.

&lt;strong&gt;My questions to all of the addresses&lt;/strong&gt; :-
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do you assume a non-windows user to not be able to afford your mid-segment notebooks?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is your intention to force Linux users into buying a Windows license?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is this an effort to form a cartel against Linux?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Question to all the notebook vendors&lt;/strong&gt; :-
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do you refund any difference amount in case the buyer does not use the license?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Question to Lenovo&lt;/strong&gt; :-
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Lenovo USA does offer an interesting range of notebooks without Windows. Does Lenovo Thailand do the same?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Question to Microsoft :-&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do you refund any unused windows License?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I am aware of the software piracy issues in Thailand, but have you ever conducted a study as to how many non-windows users own a windows license? Do you reduce this number when publishing piracy rates?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Please respond, via comment form below in English only. The replies would help me decide weather or not to get a new notebook here in Thailand or order it in the States or Singapore, potentially making the Thai Government suffer a loss of tax revenue.

PS : Apologies to other companies who fit my criteria and I missed them out! They are also free to respond.

Regards,
Sajal Kayan

Update 1 : Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bact&#34;&gt;@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bact.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;bact&lt;/a&gt; for translating to Thai and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blognone.com/node/8123&#34;&gt;publishing on blognone&lt;/a&gt;.

Update 2 : Online discussions at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blognone.com/node/8117&#34;&gt;blognone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.ubuntuclub.com/hardware/linux-notebooks/&#34;&gt;ubuntuclub&lt;/a&gt;.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangkok Bank is busy sucking Microsoft&#39;s &#39;certain body part&#39;</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/bangkok-bank-is-busy-sucking-microsofts-certain-body-part.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 11:07:30 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/bangkok-bank-is-busy-sucking-microsofts-certain-body-part.html</guid>
      <description>Until today i used to be a big fan of Bangkok Bank. In fact everyone in my family and even their companies have been using Bangkok Bank as the primary bank, in many cases their only Bank. I was quite happy with their service, only recently opened an account in another bank for certain cool features that they have which is not the point of my rant here.

So... what changed today? Well I tried to do my first login to my BizIBanking (yeah lame buzzword) account. Following the instructions in the email, i clicked login and instead of the login screen I got...

&lt;img src=&#34;/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/bbl-error.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bangkok Bank supports IE only&#34; /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
This is quite lame. I thought that one of the biggest banks wont try to push down an American capitalist product down the throat of not so rich Thai users, there must be a mistake. So i called up their friendly call center. After numerous IVR selections I finally got thru to their friendly staff.
(approximate conversation - my memory gets weaker when my head gets hot!)

Me : My new BizIbanking account doesnt work. I use firefox and it says I must use IE.
... at this point he made me restart my browser and try to login again. i told him it doesnt work and reminded him i use linux and firefox and dont have IE.
He : Oh, sorry sir. The script of the website is works on PC only. So you have to use IE.
Me : But i am using a Linux PC which has Firefox on it.
He : You must use IE
Me : But windows is unsafe. No computer in my office has windows. windows and IE is easily hackable, do you want my account to be hacked?
He : but the script is made for PC....
Me : I have recently opened account at K-Bank and they dont have any such thing
He : because they use another script
Me : Aha... so i must use K-Bank for my company accounts then.
HE : Have a Good Day.

At this point I nearly stormed out of my office to goto the bank to close my account, then i realized its past the banks closing hours. I decided to play with user agents. I changed my user agent to &#34;IE 7 on Vista&#34; using the User Agent Switcher firefox plugin.

&lt;img src=&#34;/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/user-agent.png&#34; alt=&#34;User Agent IE on Vista&#34; /&gt;

Changing User agent, everything works fine!!!

&lt;img src=&#34;/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/bbl-works.png&#34; alt=&#34;BBL now works on Firefox!&#34; /&gt;

Most such websites usually don&#39;t work on Firefox as their programmers are lazy.. but in this case it does work on Firefox. I really wonder what is their hidden agenda behind attempting (poorly) to block firefox users from visiting their site???

I need a windows box at my office to do some graphics stuff, can I get the bank to pay for the license since they force people to use Microsoft&#39;s bloatware?

Moral of the story : Usually when people say that &#34;I can&#39;t switch to Linux cause xxx site doesn&#39;t work&#34; they think its the fault of the software. They must realize that usually it is not the fault of the software, but rather some evil corporation serving their wasted interests.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Negotiate - Tips for Yahoo!</title>
      <link>http://www.sajalkayan.com/how-to-negotiate-tips-for-yahoo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 14:04:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sajalkayan.com/how-to-negotiate-tips-for-yahoo.html</guid>
      <description>Awesome video reached homepage of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lopsta.com/2008/02/13/50-diggs-zu-verschenken/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;digg&lt;/a&gt; from 2 separate links!
&lt;object width=&#39;425&#39; height=&#39;345&#39; id=&#39;FiveminPlayer&#39;&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;allowfullscreen&#39; value=&#39;true&#39;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;allowScriptAccess&#39; value=&#39;always&#39;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#39;movie&#39; value=&#39;http://www.5min.com/Embeded/5794173/&#39;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&#39;http://www.5min.com/Embeded/5794173/&#39; type=&#39;application/x-shockwave-flash&#39; width=&#39;425&#39; height=&#39;345&#39; allowfullscreen=&#39;true&#39; allowScriptAccess=&#39;always&#39;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>